MinJoo Cho

Creative Interaction Technologist



ADDRESS Schopenstehl 15, Hamburg, 20095,

Germany

EMAIL m.cho@indeed-innovation.com

NATIONALITY South Korean (EU Blue card holder) PHONE +49-174-6231773

DATE / PLACE OF

1987-06-30 / Seoul

LINKS http://www.minjoolisacho.net,

LinkedIn

Profile

Minjoo Cho has graduated from M.S in Industrial Design from KAIST(Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology, South Korea) where she has received her B.S in Electrical Engineering.

Through her studies, she participated in participated in various interactive projects: Calm Automaton(A DIY Toolkit for Ambient Display), Ratchair(Furniture That Learns to Move Itself). Prior to her graduate school, she was a project member of Samsung Creative Lab(C-Lab) for Touch Music project that aimed to provide multi-sensory music player for the deaf, followed by her project management experience in Samsung Galaxy Tablet series and Google Nexus 10 at Samsung Electronics for 3 years.

Currently, she joined INDEED Innovation GmbH as a Creative Interaction Technologist. Her main interest resides in reaching and combining ideas from different fields including Design, Technology, and Art embraced with Humanity where she always believes in.

Employment History

May 2017 - Present HAMBURG AREA, GERMANY **Creative Interaction Technologist**

Indeed Innovation GmbH

As a creative interaction technologist, I explore opportunities to introduce new interactive systems (or product) to clients or share experiences/opinions towards the future and technological advance to the public. My current AI Installation, How Will AI Change You, was

exhibited at the House of Beautiful Business, Lisbon in 2017.

Jun 2013 - Oct 2014

Creative Lab

SUWON, SOUTH KOREA Samsung Electronics

A developer/program planner of an interdisciplinary project in Samsung Electronics. Designing

sound visualisation tools for the deaf.

http://www.minjoolisacho.net/portfolio/gallery-c-lab.html

Jan 2011 - Dec 2014 SUWON, SOUTH KOREA Production Manager Samsung Electronics

A product manager of Samsung Tablets throughout the whole product life cycle. Responsible for Nexus 10, a collaborative project with Google HQ Handled two Samsung tablet projects (GALAXY Note10.1, GALAXY Tab3 10.1)

Internships

Oct 2009 — Feb 2010 KYOTO, JAPAN

Research Intern

ATR(Advanced Telecommunications Research Institute)

Human-Robot Verbal Interaction: Participated in the early development stage of a listener robot for verbal communication with human specialised for teleoperation environment.

Aug 2009 — Oct 2009 TOKYO, JAPAN

Research Intern

Toshiba

Human-Robot Verbal Interaction Human-Robot Nonverbal Interaction: Development of a visualisation tool to display "Interest Rate" read the Robot as a response to the visual input from the user.

Education

Mar 2015 — Feb 2017 DAEJEON, SOUTH KOREA

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology

Master of Science in Industrial Design

Majored in Industrial Design, myDesignLAB. My major research interest is in introducing interactive DIY tools to invite general users (without technological knowledge) to actively participate in the design process.

The graduation project, Calm Automaton, was a DIY toolkit for ambient displays and was demonstrated in CHI 2017 (Conference on Human Factors in Computing System).

Mar 2006 — Feb 2011 DAEJEON, SOUTH KOREA

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

Courses

Nov 2018 - Jan 2019

Machine Learning

Coursera

Languages Korean English Japanese Chinese German German

Skills	Prototyping (Processing, Arduino, Raspberry Pi)	••••	Web development basics (P5.js, html, css, node.js)	••••
	Computer Vision (Unity 3D, Processing, Open CV, Python)	••••	Adobe (Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere Pro, After Effects)	• • • •
	3D Modeling (Rhinoseros, Fusion 360, Solidworks)	••••	3D Printing (Ultimaker)	• • • •
			Rendering (Keyshot 5)	• • • • •
	Machine Learning	$\bullet \bullet \circ \circ \circ$, , , , , , , , , , , , , , , , , , ,	
	Computer Language (C, C#, Java)	••••		

Hobbies

Hand Drawing & Caligraphy, Music (Violin, Ukulele, Song recording), Reading books (Aesthetics, Philosophy)

Projects & Publications

Nov 2017 — Nov 2017 HAMBURG

How Will Al Change You

Today, we humans are standing on the verge of a major technological shift. Scientists, technologists, and others are developing deep learning machine intelligence, to boost our own intelligence, and help streamline processes; yet these developments could have uncontrollable consequences. Where this could draw us is up for discussion, therefore, the installation, How Will Al Change You, gives participants an opportunity to be "The Thinker", reflecting on personal and collective futures with intelligent machines.

May 2017 — May 2017 COLORADO

Calm Automaton: A DIY Toolkit for Ambient Displays

Minjoo Cho and Daniel Saakes. 2017. Calm Automaton: A DIY Toolkit for Ambient Displays. In *Proceedings of the 2017 CHI Conference Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems* (CHI EA '17). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 393-396. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1145/3027063.3052968

Aug 2016 — Aug 2016 ANAHEIM

Ratchair: furniture learns to move itself with vibration.

Tetiana Parshakova, Minjoo Cho, Alvaro Cassinelli, and Daniel Saakes. 2016. Ratchair: furniture learns to move itself with vibration. In *ACM SIGGRAPH 2016 Emerging Technologies* (SIGGRAPH '16). ACM, New York, NY, USA, Article 19, 2 pages. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1145/2929464.2929473

Sep 2015 — Sep 2015 KWANGJU Sketching in virtual reality for rapid and situated idea generation

Cho, MJ., Lee, B, Min, J., Saakes, D.P. Sketching in virtual reality for rapid and situated idea generation In KSDS Fall Conference 2015.

Apr 2009 — Apr 2009 DAEJEON

Animal Robot Interaction for PetCaring

Seung-Hwan Choi, Duckhwan Kim, Joonwoo Kim, Minjoo Cho, "Animal Robot Interaction for PetCaring", Computational Intelligence in Robotics and Automation (CIRA), 2009

Mar 2019 — Jun 2019 HAMBURG

Brain Composer

This project explores the possibility of the brain interface in musical applications. The short musical melody extracted from the human brain signal triggers Al-Engine that has been trained to produce music in the style of Bach (Music Style Transfer). The generated music then transmit the signal to the punching machine that produces 30 note music strip.

Talks

Jul 2019 — Jul 2019 HAMBURG

Job Talk, Forward Festival

Nina Kirst, senior editor from PAGE, I spoke on the opening day of Forward Festival as part of the PAGE Job Talks to describe my work as a Creative Interaction Technologist at Indeed, on design, artificial intelligence, and how both are related and fertilized. Here's more info.

https://page-online.de/branche-karriere/page-auf-dem-forward-festival-in-hamburg/

Jul 2019 — Jul 2019 HAMBURG

Job Talk, ADC Festival

Creative careers take a variety of ways. Minjoo Cho led from the Korean Advanced Institute of Science and Technology in Daejeon to Hamburg to the innovation agency Indeed. Since 2017, she has been working as a creative interaction technologist on the topic of artificial intelligence, among other things.

https://page-online.de/branche-karriere/wir-reden-tacheles-die-page-job-talks-auf-dem-adc-festival/

Feb 2019 — Feb 2019 HAMBURG

Woman in Tech Hamburg : Design, Technology, Art - the Convergence of Adjacent Fields

This women in tech meetup discusses how women are leading the charge at increasing innovation within their respective industries. Join our Disrupt meetup for women in tech community in Hamburg to learn more about how women are revolutionizing the technology sector and influencing the success of other women and motivating them to pursue career development, personal development, skill development and continuous learning opportunities.

TOPIC:

Putting the HER in "HERO": Why We Need More Women in Tech

Sep 2018 - Sep 2018

FIRESIDE CHAT: Toast to the Art in Artificial Intelligence

HAMBURG

While institutions and associations are still struggling with digitalization and transformation, artists are using their work to focus social attention to current problems and develop a variety of solutions and new approaches. That's why we want to let the creatives have their say-in parallel with the scientific and economic discussion—away from any idyllization. With Roman Lipski, Christian "Mio" Loclair and Minjoo Cho, we will discuss which vacancy Al can fill and how it enriches the work of creatives.

Related articles:

http://www.indeed-innovation.com/journal/design-technology-and-art-the-fertility-of-adjacent-fields

Jun 2018 — Jun 2018 HAMBURG

Panel Discussion: Mind the Progress

"Mind the Progress" discusses the relationship between content and technology, creativity and digitisation. As one of the four panels, I share opinion about how does technological advance influence content and how does content impact technology. http://www.mindtheprogress.de/speaker/

Extra-curricular activities

Aug 2007 — Aug 2008

DAEJEON, SOUTH KOREA

Workshop Leader

ICISTS-KAIST

An organising committee member of ICISTS-KAIST, an international conference on interdisciplinary fields.

- A Program Chair of the workshop session "Human-Robot Symbiotic Society"
- Webpage : http://icists.org/

Awards

Mar 2015 – Feb 2017 National Science & Technology Scholarship

Full scholarship for graduate programme

Jun 2006 – Mar 2010 National Science & Technology Scholarship

Full scholarship for undergraduate programme

Apr 2004 – Apr 2005 Lee Geon Hee, Samsung CEO Scholarship